Contact

priyanshi417@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/priyanshisharma-181b6b85 (LinkedIn) github.com/priyanshisharma/ (Other) leetcode.com/priyanshi417/ (Other) www.hackerrank.com/priyanshi417 (Other)

Top Skills

Creative Writing

C++

Python (Programming Language)

Languages

Hindi (Native or Bilingual)
German (Limited Working)
English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Baseline: Data, ML, Al Machine Learning APIs

AWS Fundamental Course in the AWS Machine Learning Scholarship

DAT263x : Introduction to Artificial

Intelligence

DAT249x: Ethics and Law in Data and Analytics

Honors-Awards

CodeUtsava'20 winner || SIH 2020 Finalist

Priyanshi Sharma

Computer Science and Engineering Sophomore at NIT Raipur Greater Noida

Summary

Hi, I am Priyanshi Sharma, a sophomore student pursuing my undergraduate degree in Computer Science and Engineering at National Institute of Technology, Raipur.

I have looked into and worked around an immense variety of technologies such as back-end using Django REST Framework, front-end using React, machine learning, chatbots using AIML and Dialogflow et cetera alongside being pretty active and participating in events that encourage me to learn. I'm always willing to participate in something that helps me learn and grow.

I primarily use C++ for practicing Data Structures and Algorithms and Python for Backend Development.

Participation and efforts aid my problem solving skills, no situation, no question is too difficult to not be solved. I also have strong foundations of data structures, algorithms and coding fundamentals which help me understand and alleviate problems.

I am blessed to live in a world of technology which aids my effort and gives wider exposure. Consistently pursuing this developed adaptability in me, self-respect and self-awareness such that I take my time to truly understand and bring out the best of anything I set my eyes at.

I also have a knack for writing in English and Hindi, which actually makes my explanations sharp, understandable and helpful.

I have had a journey full of learning, and am looking forward to learn and grow!

Experience

OpenGenus Foundation Software Developer, Intern April 2020 - Present (5 months)

OpenGenus Foundation is an open-source non-profit community.

- I've been enriching their resource with some articles, that can be read on my author profile.
- · I also created a chatbot in AIML.

Entrepreneurship Cell, NIT Raipur

1 year 5 months

Tech Manager April 2020 - Present (5 months)

Raipur, Chhattisgarh, India

- Currently working and guiding willing people to work on the backend of Teesco-A volunteer management system.
- I also help promote Open Source with E-Cell NITRR Opensource.
- I am also responsible for other backend development tasks such as developing the Backend for our Website and Android App.

PR and Marketing Executive April 2019 - April 2020 (1 year 1 month) Raipur Area, India

- Worked on overall successful conduction of E-Summit 2k19
- Interacted with a few college's deans and directors in order to share our vision and extend mentorship in setting their own entrepreneurship cells at their respective colleges.
- Worked directly on Ignition The B-Model competition , coordinating between various parties involved i.e. mentors, participants
- Worked in Innovation Manthan Helped coordinate participants and facilitate judgement rounds for this innovative project exhibition
- Worked in B-Quiz Formed questions for the business quiz onsite, also helped in smooth conduction of the onsite quiz. Prepared and hosted weekly B-Quizzes on Dare2Compete as well.

Public & Media Relations Cell, NIT Raipur 1 year 8 months

Core-Coordinator August 2020 - Present (1 month)

• I continue to work as an English Editor for all operations of PMRC.

• I also guide new members that work under me as a part of the Editorial Team of Mirror-The Newsletter of NIT Raipur

Coordinator

January 2019 - August 2020 (1 year 8 months)

- I'm the Content Editor of Mirror-The Newsletter of NIT Raipur
- I've worked as an English editor for all operations by PMRC.

IEEE Student Branch NIT Raipur

Documentation Executive

March 2019 - June 2020 (1 year 4 months)

Raipur Area, India

- I was responsible for the writing the content that came alongside the Student Branch's releases (website(s) content, captions etc.)
- I was also party to the successful conduction Aptrivia An olympiad for students across the state, and Chhattisgarh's first IEEE International conference ICPC2T 2020.

Interact Club, NIT Raipur

Executive

January 2019 - January 2020 (1 year 1 month)

- I was party to conducting several quizzes.
- I also made several quiz questions on a regular basis.

CYBER CLUB - DPS Greater Noida

President

May 2017 - March 2018 (11 months)

I was responsible for the smooth conduction of inter-school and intra-school technology related events including Nexus-the Cyber Fest of our School.

Education

National Institute of Technology Raipur

Bachelors of Technology, Computer Science (2018 - 2022)

Delhi Public School, Greater Noida

Senior Secondary Education · (2008 - 2018)